# SARAH WHITAKER

Deputy Program Manager: Managing Teams For ROI-Growing Results

+1-435-210-6714 elonmusk@fakemail.com linkedin.com/in/georgelgarcia6 Coral Gables, FL

#### SUMMARY

Deputy Program Manager overseeing the work of 100 team members in administration and IT. Highly experienced in creating program strategy around KPIs, goals, deadlines, and tight budgets to increase profit margins by an AVG of 25K/ year. Systematic approach towards monitoring progress and reporting, thus ensuring that client is always updated on time with program progression.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Deputy Program Manager

Coral Gables, FL 2015 - Ongoing

Torphy vision is to create technology that makes life better for everyone, everywhere — every person, every organization, and every community around the globe.

- Charted \$40+ million in FP&A while driving performance accountability for 21 manufacturing plants globally
- Led the 50+ member technical and 25 member admin teams to achieve results
- Created individual system to monitor how the program develops with a focus on each individual team member and department
- Experienced in documenting program progress with various, detailed status reports for clients

Port St Joe, FL Project Manager 2013 - 2015

Harvey is one of the world's leading medical technology companies

- Proiects created \$20+ Million in incremental revenue during the first two years
- Created and manages new Vendor Media Package which generated \$364,000 in revenue within the first 6 months
- Delivered 30% gross margin increase

Taguig, PH Junior Project Manager

2012 - 2013

Grimes is a global humanitarian organization empowering people to recover from crisis, build better lives and transform their communities for good.

- Improved on time delivery by over 60% by implementing a platform to streamline the work of the customer service department
- Structured and implemented quality assurance process through KPIs to reduce data labelling errors by 8%
- Oversaw the work of 10 team members to deliver all strategic steps within the project on time

### **SKILLS**

Analytics, Executive Alignment, Project Management, Risk Assesment

### **EDUCATION**

Coral Gables, FL **MBA** 2022 - Ongoing University of Miami

### Bachelor of Science in Global Business Management

Loretto, MN Saint Francis University 2010 - 2014

### **STRENGTHS**

## **Budget Strategy**

Success in managing programs by strategizing budget and allocating appropriate human and financial resources. Always strict about following KPIs within the overall strategy.

### Status Reporting

Prepared 850+ status reports, quickly and effectively, to make sure all parties are updated regarding progress and deadlines.

### Time Management

Planning each program development six months ahead to make the most out of all provided resources. This has optimized the budget and cut back LEAN waste by 65%.

> Powered by CV Enhancy